Guide to the Records of the Institute of African American Affairs RG.9.8
New York University Archives
- Series III: Earl S. Davis Correspondence
  - IAAA Minority Advisory Council, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - IAAA Staff Meetings, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Jazz Seminars, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - King, Jr., Dr. Martin Luther Association, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - King, Jr., Dr. Martin Luther Memorial Ceremony, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - King, Jr., Dr. Martin Luther Memorial Ceremony, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - King, Jr., Dr. Martin Luther Memorial Ceremony, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Citicorp/NYU Business Career Forum - Forms, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Citicorp/NYU Business Career Forum - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - IAAA For Your Information, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Leadership Workshop - Minority Advisory Council (MAC), 1980 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Minority Student Award, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Minority Student Recruitment at NYU, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - The NY Urban Coalition, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Organization of Black Women (OBW), 1980 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Orientation, NYU, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Secretarial Recruitment, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - A Social Worker's Critique of the Afro-American Experience by Mary Hall, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Survey of Black Studies Courses Offered throughout the University From 1970-1979 and Summary, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Survey of Black Studies Courses Offered throughout the University From 1970-1979 and Summary, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Survey of Black Studies Courses Offered throughout the University From 1970-1979 and Summary, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - Survey of Black Studies Courses Offered throughout the University From 1970-1979 and Summary, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Survey of Black Studies Courses Offered throughout the University From 1970-1979 and Summary, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - Survey of Black Studies Courses Offered throughout the University From 1970-1979 and Summary, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - ABFA Correspondence, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 35)
  - ABFA Minutes of Meetings, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - Afro-American and Related Courses at NYU, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - Black Scholars Lecture Series Correspondence, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 38)
  - Black Scholars Lecture Series Questionnaire, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 39)
  - Black Scholars Lecture Series Speakers: Thomas S. Jacobs, "Criminal Justice System", 1981 (Box 26, Folder 40)
  - Black Scholars Lecture Series Speakers: Michelle Wallace, "Black Macho and the Myth of the Superwoman", 1981 (Box 26, Folder 41)
  - Black Student Organizations at NYU, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 42)
  - Black Student Service Center, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 43)
  - Citicorp/NYU Business Career Forum for Minority Undergraduate Students, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence - E. Davis, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 45)
  - Fundraising, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 46)
  - Girls Town, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 47)
  - IAAA Advisory Committee, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 48)
  - IAAA Advisory Board, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 49)
  - IAAA Advisory Council, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 50)
  - IAAA Annual Report, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 51)
  - IAAA Black Choir, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 52)
  - IAAA For Your Information, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 53)
  - IAAA Minority Advisory Council, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 54)
  - IAAA Office Move, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226044 1
  - IAAA Office Move, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Minority Student Association Correspondence, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Monograph Series, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - UNESCO, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Williams, Sylvia "KUUMBA": Blacks in Theatre, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Benin Exhibition Catalog Publicity, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - "Black Theatre Forum: A Total Perspective" Questionnaires RESTRICTED, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Catholic Interracial Council of NY, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, E. Davis, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Funding Resources, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - IAAA Annual Report, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - IAAA Annual Report, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - IAAA Annual Report, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - IAAA Annual Report, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - IAAA Brochure, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - IAAA Library Books Receipts, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - The International Law Review of Developing Nations (ILRDN) Journal Proposal, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - National Urban League, Inc. Disease Prevention/Health Promotion in Urban Black Communities Project Advisory Committee, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Press Releases of IAAA Events, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Reservations, IAAA, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - UNESCO, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Black Student Organizations at NYU, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - African American Book Resources and Listing, 1980-1983 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Black Politics: Compilation of Articles Ranging from 1972-1983 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Black Social Workers Research, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Black Student Organizations, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Black Student Organizations, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Black Studies and Related Courses, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Burrows, Vinnie - Profile, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Community Groups / organizations, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, Earl Davis, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Film, Television and Art, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226045 8
  - Film, Television and Art, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Funding Resources, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - HEOP Higher Education Opportunities Program Background Information, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - IAAA Annual Report, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - News Articles Sports Related, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - NYU Photos, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Petty Cash Vouchers and Receipts, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Purchasing, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Research on Afro-American Adult Development "Journey Through Transitions" Questionnaire, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Transfiguration Lutheran Church, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Transfiguration Lutheran Church, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - UNESCO, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - UNESCO, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - American Committee on Africa, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Black Lifestyles Course/School of Social Work, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Brown Plus Thirty Conference Sponsored by Metro Center, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Citicorp/NYU Business Career Forum for Minority Undergraduate Students, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Community Groups / Organizations, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Congressional Black Caucus, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence - Trisha Brown, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence - Barbara Burce, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence - Earl S. Davis, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Course Listing, Black Studies and Related Courses, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - HEOP Higher Education Opportunities Program, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - IAAA Event Newspaper Ads, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - IAAA Annual Report, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - IAAA Annual Report, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - IBM Recruitment, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Jackson, Jesse, 1983-1984 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Morrison, Toni, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - NYU Black Student Organizations Correspondence, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - NYU Black Student Organizations Publicity, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - Petty Cash Vouchers and Receipts, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 34)
  - Petty Cash Vouchers and Receipts, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 35)
  - Piper, Ralph, NYU Student - Term Paper, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 36)
  - UNESCO, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Gerald Spence, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226046 6
  - AEJ Correspondence, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Association of Black Women in Higher Education, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Bibliography of NYU Dissertations of Afro-American Subjects, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Black Student Organizations, NYU, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Black Studies Programs in USA, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Brazil, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Resources Network, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - HCOP, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Intercollegiate Sports Committee, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Petty Cash Vouchers and Receipts, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Dr. Reginald R. Rison, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Rod Rodgers Dance Company, Inc., 1985 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Student Questionnaire, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - UNESCO, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - U.S. Navy Recruitment, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - U.S. Navy Recruitment, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - University of Missouri Recruitment, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - University of Texas-Exchange Program, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Dean Davis AEJ Correspondence 1985 (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - AEJ Correspondence, Earl Davis, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - AEJ Correspondence, Earl Davis, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226047 4
  - AEJ Correspondence, Earl Davis, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - NYU Black Student Organizations, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Petty Cash Vouchers and Receipts, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Black Student Organizations/NYU, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Earl S. Davis, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Afro-American and Hispanic Student Leadership Meeting, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Black Music, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Tenth Annual Black Faculty/Student Basketball Game, Feb 25, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Community Lectures Series III, Mar 24, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., Memorial Concert, Apr 4, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Percy Sutton, Apr 13, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Diane Lacey: Community Lecture Series IV, Apr 25, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Black Women's Conference, Apr 30, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Black Women's Conference, Apr 30, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Black Women's Conference, Apr 30, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Black Women in Higher Education, 5th Annual Conference, May 5, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Dr. Yosef Alfredo Antonion - Ben Jochannan, May 17, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Woody King Loeb-Eisner and Lubin, Jul 15, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Kenyan Youth Dance Group, Oct 5, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Kenyan Youth Dance Group, Oct 5, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - IAAA Calendars, 1983-1984 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Community Lecture Series I - Minter, Dr. Thomas K., Oct 17, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Dr. Juanita Howard, "The Dilemma of Black Women," Fall, Oct 25, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Black Studies Programs in U.S., Jun 7, 1905 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - AEJ - A. Peter Bailey, Mar 7, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - IAAA Annual Report, 1980-1981 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - Black Study Courses, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Black Studies Research Materials, undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226048 2
  - Black Studies Program NYU, undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Black Studies Information, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Alumni List, 1985 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Earl Davis, Black Alumni Project, undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - NYU Alumni Flyers, Notices, etc., 1988-1989 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Dilemmas for Black Americans, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Monograph Reject Letters, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Monograph Editorial Committee Folder, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Monograph Receipt Letters, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Monograph Committee Minutes, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Monograph Memos, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Monographs To Be Reviewed, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Monograph Manuscripts, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Reviewed Manuscripts and Evaluations, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226049 0
  - Monographs To Be Reviewed, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Editorial Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Editorial Committee Monographs, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Monograph Series 1979-82 Published Monographs, 1979-1982 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - First Monograph Series Published MSS Copies of Papers, undated (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - First Monograph Series Letters, Memos, Other Information, undated (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Existing MSS First Monograph Series, Use for 1984 Consideration (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Monograph Series Correspondence, Earl Davis, undated (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Monograph Tentative Acceptances, undated (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - More Monograph Information, undated (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - First Edited Copies - ESD Monograph Series, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Monograph Series Papers Submitted by Prospective Authors, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Monograph Series Papers Submitted by Prospective Authors, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226050 8
  - Monograph Series Papers Submitted by Prospective Authors, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Monograph Series Papers Submitted by Prospective Authors, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Monograph Series Papers Submitted by Prospective Authors, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Monograph Series Papers Submitted by Prospective Authors, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Monograph Series Papers Submitted by Prospective Authors, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Monograph Series Papers Submitted by Prospective Authors, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Monograph Series Papers Submitted by Prospective Authors, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Monograph Series Papers Submitted by Prospective Authors, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Monograph Series Papers Submitted by Prospective Authors, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Monograph Series Papers Submitted by Prospective Authors, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Monograph Series Papers Submitted by Prospective Authors, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Journals, Reports, Guides, Magazines, undated (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Labor and Education, undated (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Articles and Essays, undated (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - New Federal Theatre - Woodie King, Carib Arts Ensemble, 1989 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Ann Marcus - Recruitment Minority Affairs, undated (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Nutrament Scholarship, Apr 26, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Black Church Conference, undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226051 6
  - Newspaper/Magazine Articles, ESD, undated (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Sterling Brown Tribute - Woodie King, Feb 1986 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Caribbean Culture Center, undated (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - SCE Course - Carolyn McKenzie, Jul 1990 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Minority Recruitment, undated (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Untitled Folder, undated (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Annual Report, 1983-1984 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Black Studies, undated (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Martin Luther King, Jr., Scholarship, undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Black Studies Information, undated (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Black Lifestyles, Undergraduate, Mar 21, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - BSSC, undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226052 4
  - Choral Group, undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Relocation Plans, 1979-1980 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - 3 Benin Catalogues, undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
- Series IV: Audiovisual Recordings
  - Subseries A: The Soul of Reason Audio Recordings
    Arrangement
    The Soul of Reason Audio Recordings are arranged chronologically by date of broadcast.
    Scope and Contents
    This sub-series contains 266 audio recordings of The Soul of Reason radio shows that aired between 1971 and 1978, which represents a portion of the shows that aired on commercial radio station WNBC and were rebroadcast on NYU's station WNYU. Interviewees included politicians, medical professionals, educators, professional athletes, writers, performers, and contemporary visual artists who discussed issues affecting the Black and Puerto Rican communities, and economically-deprived neighborhoods of New York City. The American Bicentennial, the creation of the Gateway National Recreation Area, the relocation of the New York Public Library's Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture, and the effects of New York City's fiscal crisis on education, employment, and healthcare for these communities were regularly discussed topics. Repeat guests included Vice Chairman of the Democratic National Committee Basil Paterson; President of the New York Urban Coalition Arthur Barnes; Editor for Black Sports Magazine Allan Barron; Editor-at-Large for Black Enterprise magazine Pat Patterson; jazz pianist Mary Lou Williams; authors Nathan Huggins and John O. Killens; and doctors John Holloman, June Christmas, and Ivory Carr.
    Historical Note
    The Soul of Reason (SoR) was a half-hour, talk-show format radio show that aired from 1971-1986 as a result of a collaboration between the commercial radio station WNBC and New York University's station WNYU. The host of the program, Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. was also the Director of the Institute of Afro-American Affairs (IAAA) at NYU at the time. The show's mission was to be "a showcase for Black scholarship….to examine the foundations of African-American thought from a variety of areas," according to founding documents for the show. During each episode, Brown conducted an informal, back and forth dialogue with a variety of professionals, mainly from the New York City area, who spoke personally to the unique challenges of the Black experience. These shows initially aired at 10pm and 12am on WNBC and were rebroadcast a few weeks later on WNYU.
    - Moses, Gil -- Director of the Broadway play Ain't Supposed to Die a Natural Death., 1971 October 26; RG9.8-86; Format: Reel TRT: 29:00 (Box 41, Folder 86)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Gil Moses discuss the Broadway play Ain't Supposed to Die a Natural Death.
    - Walker, Jim -- Book Editor and Advertising Manager for Black Creation magazine., 1973 January 8; RG9.8-150; Format: Reel TRT: 28:50 (Box 53, Folder 150, Box Access 14, Disk 16)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Jim Walker discuss themes in contemporary Black writing and the forms of Black literature they feel are most expressive of the Black experience.
    - Fortune, Dr. Hilda -- Professor of Sociology at York College of the City University of New York., 1973 January 14; RG9.8-166; Format: Reel TRT: 28:50 (Box 53, Folder 166)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Dr. Hilda Fortune discuss whether or not the City University of New York is meeting the needs of minority and low-income youth, including if adequate counseling services are available. They also discuss the diversity of CUNY's faculty.
    - Gunn, Bill -- playwright and Director of the Black Picture Show., 1973 March 25; RG9.8-134; Format: Reel TRT: 28:50 (Box 53, Folder 134)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Bill Gunn discuss the mid-life crisis theme present in Gunn's play the Black Picture Show, performed at the Vivian Beaumont Theater.
    - Dorsey, Carolyn -- instructor at the New York University School of Education and fellow at the Institute of Afro-American Affairs of New York University., 1973 June 19; RG9.8-88; Format: Reel TRT: 28:50 (Box 41, Folder 88)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Carolyn Dorsey discuss whether or not Black studies has fullfilled its potential and identify what they believe to be the areas of greatest importance within the field of Black studies.
    - Davis, Nat -- Assistant Director for the community-oriented drug education program of Harlem Teams for Self-Help., 1973 July 29; RG9.8-2; Format: Reel TRT: 28:45 (Box 40, Folder 2)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Nat Davis address the problem of drug addiction in inner-city communities like Harlem.
    - Murray, James P. -- film critic, Film Editor of the New York Amsterdam News, and Editor of Black Creation., 1973 August 19; RG9.8-85; Format: Reel TRT: 28:50 Vinegar smell (Box 41, Folder 85, Box Access 14, Item 15)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and James P. Murray discuss the business aspect of the entertainment industry, including how commercialism affects the relationship between Black performing artists and business entrepreneurs.
    - Barron, Allan -- Publisher of Black Sports Magazine., 1973 August 26; RG9.8-5; Format: Reel TRT: 28:50 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Allan Barron discuss the Black Sports Hall of Fame, created by Black Sports Magazine.
    - Russell, Harvey C. -- Vice President of PepsiCo and co-chairmen of the Congressional Black Caucus Dinner., 1973 September 16; RG9.8-83; Format: Reel TRT: 28:50 (Box 41, Folder 83)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Harvey C. Russell discuss the purpose of the Congressional Black Caucus and supporters of their annual fundraising dinner in Washington D.C.
    - Finch, Connie -- sophomore student from New York University involved in Black student affairs., 1973 September 25; RG9.8-82; Format: Reel TRT: 28:15 (Box 41, Folder 82)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Connie Finch discuss contemporary Black student political views and how they differ from the Black student activism of the 1960s.
    - Anglada, Mario -- Executive Director of ASPIRA New York., 1973 November 13; RG9.8-94; Format: Reel TRT: unknown (Box 41, Folder 94)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Mario Anglada discuss social problems of Puerto Rican youth, including competition between Blacks and Puerto Ricans for educational funding. They also discuss how non-profit organizations like ASPIRA can help with these issues.
    - Covington, William -- Special Assistant to the Project Director of the Urban League's Youth Enrichment Program., 1973 November 20; RG9.8-6; Format: Reel TRT: unknown (Box 40, Folder 6)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and William Covington discuss how the Urban League's Youth Enrichment Program tries to help youth placed on probabtion by the courts through activities like outdoor living and education.
    - Taylor, Cecil -- musician., 1973 November 27; RG9.8-98; Format: Reel TRT: 28:50 (Box 41, Folder 98)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Cecil Taylor discuss the themes, forms, and meanings of Black music.
    - Clarke, Richard -- Founder of Richard Clarke Associates., 1973 December 4; RG9.8-138; Format: Reel TRT: 28:50 (Box 53, Folder 138)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Richard Clarke discuss employement opportunities, including those in major corporations, for recent Black college graduates.
    - Lacy, Diane -- Coordinator of the National Conference on Drug Abuse., 1973 December 11; RG9.8-81; Format: Reel TRT: 28:50 (Box 41, Folder 81)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Diane Lacy discuss some of the ways the National Conference on Drug Abuse could affect drug problems in America. They also discuss the role of the professional woman in eliminating such problems within the Black community.
    - Williams, Charles -- Assistant Council of the NAACP Legal Defense Fund., 1973 December 16; RG9.8-55; Format: Reel TRT: unknown (Box 52, Folder 55)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Charles Williams discuss racism and the guidelines the NAACP Legal Defense Fund uses when selecting discrimination cases for representation.
    - Cintron, Umberto -- Executive Producer of the television show Realidades., 1973 December 18; RG9.8-101; Format: Reel TRT: 28:50 (Box 41, Folder 101)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Umberto Cintron discuss the problems minority-oriented programs like Realidades, Soul, Black Journal, and Black Arts face in order to remain on television.
    - Figueroa, Jose-Angel -- poet and author of the book East 110th Street., 1973 December 30; RG9.8-97; Format: Reel TRT: 28:50 (Box 41, Folder 97)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Jose-Angel Figueroa discuss Figueroa's thoughts, feelings, and experiences of East Harlem (El Barrio), which are also included in his book East 110th Street.
    - Bertram, Cliff -- track coach at New York University., 1974 January 14; RG9.8-54; Format: Reel TRT: 28:50 (Box 52, Folder 54)